<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android | Alex Hogen</title>
    <link>https://ahogen.github.io/tags/android/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ahogen.github.io/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>android</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Alexander Hogen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ahogen.github.io/images/icon_hu41297bf952fcc5965d442cd00908f20d_1356_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>android</title>
      <link>https://ahogen.github.io/tags/android/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel 3 Personal Concerns</title>
      <link>https://ahogen.github.io/post/pixel-3-personal-concerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ahogen.github.io/post/pixel-3-personal-concerns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to keep up with some of the Pixel 3 rumors and leaks that have
been coming out. My Nexus 5X just took a turn for the worst. After 2 years and
1 month of use, it suddenly slowed and then started bootlooping &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
And, no, I was not made aware of the class-action lawsuit. I had bought an extended
damage protection plan, but that expired just a month before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m the market for a new phone. We&amp;rsquo;re likely 2 months away from the next
Google phone, the Pixel 3, but there are some things that really bother me about
this potential option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No 3.5mm headphone jack. A major negative for a constant audio enthusiast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obscenely large notch. I&amp;rsquo;m paying for a very nice, high-density screen. I
really dislike the idea of it being defiled by a notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially smaller battery compared to Pixel 2. Not as big a deal as the
other two, but would be disappointing to get the next biggest thing and
have reduced specs in a very important area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;













&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.androidcentral.com/sites/androidcentral.com/files/styles/xlarge/public/article_images/2018/08/pixel-3-xl-yuck.jpg?itok=2EnCPFmh&#34; data-caption=&#34;Pixel 3 XL leaked photos&#34;&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://www.androidcentral.com/sites/androidcentral.com/files/styles/xlarge/public/article_images/2018/08/pixel-3-xl-yuck.jpg?itok=2EnCPFmh&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Pixel 3 XL leaked photos
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s really annoying to me. The competition, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve found
so far, has a lot more negatives. The biggest name seems to be Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samsung just released it&amp;rsquo;s Galaxy S9. But, oh look, camera under-performs in
low-light conditions, battery life is inconclusive, and well&amp;hellip; Bixby &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
Also it looks like it&amp;rsquo;s got the trending notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to mention all the garbage-ware that you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of. I have a Samsung
Tab 4 which has its own calendar, contacts, and calculator; all of which are
terrible in comparison to others on the Play app store. But nope, you can&amp;rsquo;t
remove them. And, in the case of calendar and contacts, both the Samsung version
and the Google version sync data from my Google account. So both produce
notifications and suck up data, without some tweaking. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used Samsung
since, so maybe they fixed this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the Galaxy S9 is more expensive than the Pixel 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll get Android updates much less frequently than if I had a
Pixel 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardware on some phones from OnePlus, LG, and Huawei looked interesting.
However, I have a bad taste in my mouth from LG&amp;rsquo;s Nexus 5X since it bootlooped
on me. The U.S. Government highly recommends not getting a Huawei phone due to
spying concerns &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. OnePlus and Xiaumi are also China-based
companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data-mining for advertisement purposes is distasteful to me, but if there was
super compelling hardware, I might not care. However, security is a concern.
And in the world of Android, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve read, most people agree that you
need a Google phone for faster updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what am I to do? These slabs of silicon are not cheap. So if I&amp;rsquo;m going to
drop that kind of money, I feel like I should be really happy with what I
get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pixel-3-pros&#34;&gt;Pixel 3 Pros:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better security (faster updates)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less bloatware. I want the Google apps anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better camera than most competition, if it&amp;rsquo;s as good or better than Pixel 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s the new flagship, should be built for the new Android Pie, and
phone will be supported for a while (longer than Pixel 2, I would imagine).
My Nexus 5X was going to lose support here in September 2018 I believe; just
over 2 yrs after buying it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If price is comparable to the Pixel 2&amp;rsquo;s $625 starting price, then it comes in
a little cheaper than some of the Samsung flagship stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve read about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pixel-3-cons&#34;&gt;Pixel 3 Cons:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No headphone jack. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to charge any d**n bluetooth headphones either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t charge phone and listen to music with wired headphones &lt;strong&gt;unless&lt;/strong&gt; maybe
it has wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupidly obnoxious notch. Pay a premium to get little bits of pixels to throw
away?!? Err, no. I&amp;rsquo;d rather have a fully-utilized, clean, rectagular display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-would-my-ideal-phone-be&#34;&gt;What would my ideal phone be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gets updates fast. As in, same time as Pixel phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headphone jack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No notch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battery lasts all day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid 12+ MP camera with good low-light performance and HDR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t care about GPUs much since I don&amp;rsquo;t game. Just a few YouTube videos
here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIM card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports CDMA and GSM networks, so I can choose either with TracFone, like I
did with my Nexus 5X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingerprint sensor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.1&amp;rdquo; - 5.2&amp;rdquo; display &amp;ndash; I dislike large phones that won&amp;rsquo;t fit in my pockets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4-6GB RAM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32GB storage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I&amp;rsquo;m peeved because I don&amp;rsquo;t think my ideal specs are too hard to ask for.
I really actually don&amp;rsquo;t wany anything complicated. I want a good solid camera
because it&amp;rsquo;s the only one I cary with me and if I see something cool, it&amp;rsquo;s
important for me to have a tool to capture that moment clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoy my music all the time. At work and at home, both being places where I
often charge my phone as well. I want to charge the phone and play music at the
same time. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t so hard to ask for in the past; I really don&amp;rsquo;t see why I
should have to let that go now. And I dislike the idea of having a second battery
(the wireless headphones) to charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read some complaints about how this new version of Android, Android Pie,
is a pain to use &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But if this really is going to
be the future of Android, then I&amp;rsquo;d rather be running this on a Pixel 3, than
on something else from a 3rd party who may or may not be designing the hardware
to match upcoming software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m desperate for a new phone, so maybe I will just have to get a Pixel 3, because
it&amp;rsquo;s the best I can do. I really did not want to settle for &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; when
it comes to anything over $300. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep looking for other options until
October, when the Pixel 3 is expected to be released, and see if I can find
something that fits my needs better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, it&amp;rsquo;s not looking great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- an android user&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LG_smartphone_bootloop_issues#Nexus_5X&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LG_smartphone_bootloop_issues#Nexus_5X&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnet.com/reviews/samsung-galaxy-s9-review/&#34;&gt;https://www.cnet.com/reviews/samsung-galaxy-s9-review/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90218406/new-law-prohibits-government-from-using-zte-huawei-gear&#34;&gt;https://www.fastcompany.com/90218406/new-law-prohibits-government-from-using-zte-huawei-gear&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.androidcentral.com/pixel-3-xl-might-be-first-phone-google-i-just-dont-want&#34;&gt;https://www.androidcentral.com/pixel-3-xl-might-be-first-phone-google-i-just-dont-want&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Android Market on Coby Kyros MID7012 (or most other tablets running Android 2.3.3)</title>
      <link>https://ahogen.github.io/post/tutorial-android-market-coby-kyros-mid7012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ahogen.github.io/post/tutorial-android-market-coby-kyros-mid7012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    This &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170201091154/http://nwteche.com/alex_blog/install-android-market-on-coby-kyros-mid7012-or-most-other-tablets-running-android-2-3-3/&#34;&gt;tutorial originally appeared&lt;/a&gt;
back in 2012 on my (Alex&amp;rsquo;s) blog on Northwest Tech Experience (nwteche.com).
That website has been removed and I migrated some of my content to this new site.
I may have edited the original content for clarity.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Christmas I put the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005HUH88K&#34;&gt;Coby Kyros MID7012 tablet&lt;/a&gt; (which only runs Android 2.3.3) on my wish list. I was surprised when I actually received it! By that time, I had decided I didn’t really need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005HUH88K&#34;&gt;Kyros 7012&lt;/a&gt; and others don’t have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Play#History&#34;&gt;Android Market&lt;/a&gt; installed out of the box. It would seem like all you’d need to do is install a few .apk files and you’d be good, right? Well all but two articles I read online were not like that at all. Most required you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rooting_(Android)&#34;&gt;root&lt;/a&gt; the device. Although rooting itself can be undone, certain things done with rooting privileges cannot. Not to mention the fact that “rooting” the tablet most likely voids the warranty on the device. So, in short, it doesn’t seem like “doing it right the first time” is very popular with people installing the Android Market. That is why I wanted to throw in my two cents about this so that more people can do this right and not mess up their devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some research, I found a method that worked for me. It is based off a YouTube tutorial. If you go on YouTube, it’s the first one that pops up if you search “install android market on coby” I believe. Here’s the actual URL: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6BrWSC2uiAg&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6BrWSC2uiAg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-of-liability&#34;&gt;Release of Liability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; I, ALEXANDER HOGEN, AND ANY OTHER INDIVIDUAL OR COMPANY ASSOCIATED WITH MYSELF SHALL NOT BE HELD RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE, LOSS OF DATA, LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY OR
ANY OTHER OUTCOME AS A RESULT OF FOLLOWING THIS TUTORIAL. THE USER RECOGNIZES THAT THERE ARE CERTAIN INHERENT RISKS ASSOCIATED WITH PERFORMING THE OPERATIONS DESCRIBED IN THIS TUTORIAL AND THE USER ASSUMES FULL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY UNDESIRABLE OUTCOME DURING OR AFTER PERFORMING THE STEPS DESCRIBED ON THIS WEBSITE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put that notification up in case someone messes up their device by following this tutorial, although I &lt;em&gt;seriously&lt;/em&gt; doubt they will. These steps aren&amp;rsquo;t hard and there is no rooting or &amp;ldquo;jail-breaking&amp;rdquo; involved. Okay, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On your computer, download the “Android Market_install_files.zip” below and unzip all the files to a convenient location (say, your desktop). &lt;a href=&#34;https://ahogen.github.io/downloads/Android-Market_install_files.zip&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Market_install_files.zip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now connect the tablet to your PC and put these files on your tablet’s SD card or internal memory. If your not sure how to do this, consult your &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20130822214307/http://cobyusa.com/files/manuals/MID7012_MN.pdf&#34;&gt;product manual&lt;/a&gt; (on page 30 I think). I stuck the files in the “downloads” folder on the device itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the files have finished transferring, disconnect the tablet from your PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to your file viewer app. On my tablet, they installed “ES File Explorer”. Yours should have a similar file explorer program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now find where you put those .apk files. I put mine in the “downloads” folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, now you are going to install them in a specific order. (Just tap on the file to install. Hit “Done” after each one. &lt;strong&gt;DON’T&lt;/strong&gt; RUN THEM AFTER THEY INSTALL!) Here is the order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneTimeInitializer.apk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SetupWizard.apk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoogleServicesFramework-signed.apk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;com.android.vending.3.3.12.apk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, this step is important. &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; GO TO THE HOME SCREEN!!. Press and hold the power button on the tablet and turn it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now turn it back on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After start-up, you will see a menu with two options. Check the “Use this as default” box on the bottom, then select the option on top (“Launcher”). You don’t want to set up anything. You just want to use the regular initializer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you are connected to a wireless network (WIFI). If not, get your tablet connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that your connected, go to the Apps list (by tapping the box made of little squares that’s either on the bottom or right hand side of your screen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see the Android Market icon in this list. Go ahead and open it. Since this is the first run, you’ll need to enter your Google Account information and accept the license agreement.The Android Market will filter out most apps that won’t work with your tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should be good to go. Enjoy your new apps!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
